此视频是第三个也是最后一个视频，我们现在将在其中完成堆栈级别的漏洞攻击
0 from protostar, which we have compiled on a modern system.
在第一部分中，我们大致了解了编译代码时所做的更改。
with a more modern compiler and looked more closely at the stack cookie.
在第二部分中，我们暂时忽略了cookie，并确定了更多的利用
mitigations and developed a bypass for them.
So only one thing is left.
Finally defeating the stack cookie.
就像我们在第一个视频中提到的，如果二进制文件
is a 32 bit binary.
There are around 16 million possible values for a stack cookie.
没那么多，但1600万次处决也许是你开始想要的一个数字
optimize a bit.
虽然我不是超级快速计算方面的专家，但我决定我不想写潜在的
slow python script, but write some C code.
但就像我说的，我不是最快速度的专家，我怀疑
也许这里的瓶颈不是一个缓慢的脚本，而是需要做很多工作的内核
of stuff to execute the program over and over again.
So maybe it’s unnecessary to write C code and maybe my C code is very bad too.
但我只是想说，决定什么是最好的并不总是容易的。
approach.
Now that we said that, let’s try to approach this step by step.
First.
How do you execute a program in C. Well, there is a system call for it called exec.
但通常我们从不直接调用系统调用，而是使用提供的包装函数
by something like libc.
所以libc提供了几个不同版本的exec，但它们最终都使用
same exec syscall underneath.
在手册页上写着：
“exec（）函数系列将当前进程图像替换为新进程
形象。”
我想如果你以前从来没有想过程序是如何执行的，这听起来真的
weird.
“为什么要替换当前进程而不仅仅是执行它？
That’s so weird”.
Well that’s just how it works, that’s the execution model of Linux.
因此，在我们的案例中，我们不只是想执行并替换我们的程序，而是
want to execute the stack0 binary as a new process over and over again.
To spawn a new process we have to fork the process before we exec.
fork() creates a new process by duplicating the calling process.
The new process is referred to as the child process.
The calling process is referred to as the parent process.
还有一个有趣的地方是：C库函数和
the actual kernel.
因为版本2.3.3，而不是调用内核的fork（）系统调用，所以glibc
fork（）包装器[…]使用提供与
traditional system call.
因此，要反复执行这个过程，您要做的是：
First fork our current process.
now we have a child.
An actual new separate process.
你必须想象这段代码现在被涂鸦了，我们有两个进程在运行相同的代码，
just one runs as the child and one runs as the parent.
And you can check the return value of fork which process you are.
In the parent process you get the pid of the child.
In the child it’s just 0.
然后在子进程中，我们可以调用exec，将当前进程替换为
stack 0.
Now in our case we want to communicate with the child.
这意味着我们要将漏洞输入写入它，并读取它的输出，以确定
if we were successful.
Usually you would do this by creating pipes.
pipe（）创建一个管道，一个可用于进程间的单向数据通道
communication.
The array pipefd is used to return two file descriptors referring to the ends of the pipe.
pipefd[0] refers to the read end of the pipe.
pipefd[1] refers to the write end of the pipe.
写入管道写入端的数据由内核缓冲，直到读取为止。
from the read end of the pipe.
Basically the same pipe you can use on the commandline.
You pipe stdout from one program, cat, into the stdin of another program, grep.
That’s why we call this character a “pipe”.
So for basic stdin and stdout communication you would create two pipes.
然后，当您分叉时，由于您克隆了进程，子进程和父进程
access to the same pipe.
现在很明显，取决于你是父母还是孩子，你使用其中一个或另一个
side of it.
对于这个孩子，我们实际上要替换默认的stdin和stdout
now with those pipes.
By calling dup2.
dup2（）系统调用执行与dup（）相同的任务，
And The dup() system call creates a copy of the file descriptor.
After a successful return, the old and new file descriptors may be used interchangeably.
They refer to the same open file description and thus share everything.
但是dup2使用的不是编号最低的未使用文件描述符dup（），而是
descriptor number specified in newfd, the second paramenter.
If the descriptor newfd was previously open, it is silently closed before being reused.
所以dup2关闭当前子进程的stdin和stdout，并插入新的管道
created.
当我们执行stack0并用新的进程替换当前进程时，
like open fildescriptors stay in tact.
So the new process will use the pipes we just connected for reading input and writing output.
然后在父系统中，我们可以简单地读写管道的另一端，
thus communicate with the child process stack0.
A nice thing to do is to close the ends of the pipes you are not using in either process.
例如，我们不需要stdin管道的读取端，因为我们希望
write, send data, to the child process.
Ok.
一旦我们编写了缓冲区溢出输入，就可以等待子进程完成。
and read the output to see if we were successful.
Now here is a first big issue.
Buffering.
Libc will buffer output you write.
So the output of the child process is buffered in the process.
你可以想象，如果我们做了一个缓冲区溢出，用堆栈拧动，得到一个segfault
this buffer is lost.
The program is just dying horribly.
但也许你认为这没什么意义，因为我们在第2部分展示了
exploit theoretically works and we see the output on the shell.
We saw the modified variable message.
那么，shell看到输出有什么意义，但我告诉你
现在，我们不会用刚才编写的代码看到它了吗？
Well.
libc如何缓冲输出取决于它的管道类型
connected to.
在我们的例子中，我们刚刚使用了常规管道，libc将缓冲输出数据。
直到进程调用flush（），或者直到它被很好地填充，或者在1024之后
bytes or so.
I don’t know.
But we have neither, the output is super short and the child process never calls flush().
So what’s different on the shell.
由壳牌公司执行的钻井程序不是通过常规管道连接的，而是通过常规管道连接的。
to a pseudo terminal.
Pty.
And when libc sees.
将输出写入一个伪终端pty，然后它将刷新缓冲区（）。
upon a newline.
因为换行就像是你想要打印一行的最后指示（笑）
on the terminal output.
我认为这就像速度一样，如果不需要的话你不想冲水，但是在
terminal you want to see outputs after a newline.
这意味着，我们也可以在一个pty的上下文中执行stack0程序，以便
fool libc into flushing on every newline.
And there is a convinient libc function that does that for us.
称为forkpty（）。
函数的作用是：结合openpty（open pseudo terminal）、fork（2）（我们知道）。
and login_tty() to create a new process operating in a pseudoterminal.
The file descriptor of the master side of the pseudoterminal is returned in amaster.
So that’s really cool.
我们派生一个子进程，并已经获取文件描述符，以便与
the child process.
然后我禁用终端的一些选项，例如，我不想回显输入。
again.
例如，如果你观看我的嵌入式硬件安全CTF视频，你通常会注意到
每当我在黑板上打些东西时，我都看不到
type, that’s because I didn’t configure the terminal to echo back the characters.
While it would have been nice there, I don’t need it here.
And there are a few other options that could screw with what we want to do.
And then we also don’t have to fiddle with pipes.
So the child is just exec now.
在父级中，我们定义了缓冲溢出输入，这基本上就是我们开发的输入
最后一个视频，然后添加一些random（）函数以获取
cookie.
And place those into the buffer overflow string.
一个简单的丑陋循环来避免换行，因为这将指示输入的结束，
and we dont’ want that.
然后我们将bufferoverflow字符串写入伪终端的主文件描述器
and stack0 will read it and will get exploited.
然后我创建一个简短的循环来检查孩子的状态，但我不想阻止
等等，因为缓冲区溢出，孩子可能会死得很惨，也可能不会死，
所以我只是在一个循环中检查几次状态，如果孩子死了，我们继续，
如果我们已经等了几次，我们决定终止儿童进程，
And otherwise we sleep a bit.
Usually it shouldn’t loop much, as the child program is very short, but it’s a safety-net.
BTW. program ids, pids, are prone to race conditions in linux.
你看，我们没有直接指向子进程的句柄，我们
only have the number.
And numbers can be reused.
所以从理论上讲，我们的孩子可能已经死了，另一个像网络服务器这样的进程可能已经死了。
been executed and assigned our old pid, and then we kill it here.
And there is no better way, linux is just really ugly some times.
Anyway.
我现在要添加的另一件事是信号处理程序，如果孩子
dies or so.
我们可以在等待之后读取输出，但我们不知道为什么以及如何
might die and so forth, and I also found it to be a third slower if I do that.
So used the signal handler instead.
This handler function is called to notify us if anything happens to the child.
So when it receives a SIGCHLD.
And in the handler function we then read from the terminal the output of stack0.
首先我们读到“再试一次？“
message.
然后可能读取堆栈粉碎检测到的错误，或者成功修改
variable message.
Or maybe nothing.
Then I do an ugly check of the second output to see the success message.
If that’s the case we print it and we are done.
So now it’s basically ready.
I add some more debug output to see whats going on, add an argument to supply a seed.
and then we can compile it.
Because we want to use forkpty, we have to also link the utils library.
Here you can see how many executions we get per second per process.
This machine has only one CPU, so this will take a while, let’s come back later.
Let’s see.
Mhhm… nothing happened yet.
Maybe let’s rent a bigger server for a few hours with more CPU cores.
Mmh maybe this one.
Now to run it I do some ghetto parallelisation.
But oh what.
每秒只有9次处决，那是什么垃圾？
If you look at the processes you can see something called apport.
Apport是一个系统，它可以在发生崩溃时截获崩溃。
第一次，收集有关
崩溃和操作系统环境，
啊，所以，因为我们不断地破坏一个过程，这件事就是传递信息和减慢速度。
everything down.
Let’s disable this service.
And then let’s wait for a bit.
是啊！
See, one process output the modified variable message.
How amazing is that.
I admit not the most reliable exploit, but it worked.
I’m happy.
If you have a better exploit strategy for this here, please share it with us.
我真的很好奇还有什么技术可以用来利用这个程序
more reliable way.
Thanks guys, see you next time.